dhruvinity@outlook.com | +16282208630 | https://www.linkedin.com/in/dhruvinity

SUMMARY

Full stack Developer with experience in designing, coordinating and developing software solutions.

Programming	Java, JavaScript, Dart, Python, Golang, HTML5,
	CSS3, TypeScript, C++, Solidity
Framework	Spring, TensorFlow, Flutter, React-Native, NodeJS,
Scripting	Shell Scripting
Libraries/Tools	ReactJS, VueJS, AngularJS, Redux, Vuex, Provider,
	gin, gorm, jQuery, bootstrap, materialUI, Tensor
	Board
Databases	SQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Cloud Fire Store
GitHub	https://www.gibhub.com/dhruv1794

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Developer- Sezzle, Remote, India

April 2018 - August 2021

- Implemented effective caching rules with a combination of in-memory, browser and CDN techniques to reduce server load from ~160/sec to ~20/sec.
- Architected and automated the widget integration to reduce manual intervention as much as possible. Integration time dropped from 45 minutes to under 1 minute.
- Developed a Chrome Extension with OAuth for widget integration. Developed REST APIs with GO and use MySQL database. This tool eliminated the need of a developer for widget integration.
- Authored multiple SDKs and tools around Sezzle's widget with React, JS, HTML, CSS which are used on over 20K websites.
- Developed scrappers with Golang, gin, gorm to check merchant website for widget abnormalities.

Software Developer- Doodleblue, Chennai, India

March 2017 – April 2018

- Developed and implemented 15+ public developer APIs for User Creation and profile management. These API's have 50K plus calls a day.
- Developed REST APIs for e-commerce website using NodeJS, express and mongo DB.
- Developed frontend for a job portal using ReactJS, used Web Socket for chat integration and Redux for state management.
- Implemented design changes that increased the performance of application through optimizing and tuning DB queries.
- Converted UI/UX designs into prototypes, creating excellent interactions from designs, writing reusable content modules and maintainable code

Teacher Assistant – Northeastern University, San Jose, California

January 2022 – Present

- Teaching assistant in Machine Learning and Applied Sciences
- Assisting and grading coursework while taking informative sessions.

EDUCATION

- Masters in Information System Northeastern University | GPA 4
- BE Vellore Institute of Technology